# AbulAsar Sayyad

# **FullStack Software Engineer**

+917738279262

@ abul.asar22@gmail.com

https://abulasar.com/

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Development Engineer

#### **ID Plans**

## 10/2021 - Ongoing

Remote(Office USA)

ID Plans offers a wide range of comprehensive property management solutions to make it easier than ever to manage properties remotely.

- FullStack Engineer (Node.js, Ember and React)
- Worked on refactoring Node.js API and reduced function logic from more than 400+ lines to multiple readable and testable concerns.
- Fixed complex bugs with TDD approach.
- Improved code coverage of Node.js API and moved test cases into separate module for better performance and readability.
- Managed migrations of Dynamodb data into Mysql DataLake.

### Software Engineer

#### **SelectHub**

**1** 04/2021 - 09/2021

Remote(Office USA)

SelectHub, a technology selection management solution, eliminates the messy, error prone business of IT and software requirements compilation, vendor evaluations and sourcing by centralizing all activities on an easy-to-use, intelligent platform.

- FullStack Developer (Ruby, Elixir, Javascript)
- · Worked on Enterprise application in Ruby on Rails
- Used frontend framework Marionette-backbone for frontend oriented tasks
- Refactored few modules by removing JS generated UI with Rails SSR and improved performance of page loading.
- Worked on User Client Feedback questions sorting module.
- Looking into bug fixes related to Redis, Salesforce sync and UI enhancement etc
- · Developing API in Elixir for Vuejs app.

### Senior Software Engineer

#### **Kiprosh**

**1** 03/2018 - 03/2021

Kiprosh is a software development company crafting scalable web and mobile products.

- FullStack Developer (GoodCity- https://www.crossroads.org.hk/)
- Developed caching module for Frontend app performance
- Worked on performance of one of the App, reducing its loading time from 30 ms to 3 ms
- Upgraded Twilio voice calling feature by contributing to Open source project
- Frequently upgrade Cordova apps along with CI pipeline for iOS and Android
- · Elixir Developer (www.trackive.com)
- Developed API in Elixir and Phoenix
- Developed analytics module API

### SUMMARY

I am a FullStack developer with 6 years industry experience building web applications in HealthCare, Real-estate and E-learning. I have proficiency in JavaScript and have professional working experience with Ruby on Rails and Elixir/Phoenix. I am adaptable to work on any technology stack and constantly working to sharpen my engineering skills.

# **OPEN CONTRIBUTION**

#### ember-infinite-list

https://github.com/crossroads/ember-infinite-list

### cordova-plugin-twiliovoicesdk

https://github.com/jefflinwood/cordova-plugin-twiliovoicesdk/pull/68

#### ember-scroll-to-bottom

https://github.com/Darshan-Chauhan/ember-scroll-to-bottom/pull/1

# **SKILLS**

EmberJs	Ruby on Rails			
Javascript/ES6		Elixir/Phoenix		ОТР
Postgresql	HTML/CSS		Twilio	_
Cordova	CI	Cordova		

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer

#### **Chenoa Information Services**

**1** 03/2017 - 03/2018

Mumbai, India

Chenoa is service based company building scalable, customer-centric

- FullStack Developer (IDPlans-https://www.idplans.com/)
- Property Management real-estate Remote Web app which can monitor Real estate.
- Used Ember for UI and REST API with Nodejs backed with DynamoDB(AWS).
- · Developed Admin Panel with custom drag and drop option to manage UI for the clients of this app.
- · Frontend Developer (Dosed Daily- https://www.doseddaily.com)
- E-learning Web app for Doctors and medical practitioners.
- Managed frontend development and planning of components.
- · Developed Dynamic web app using Html and Mustache.js for app performance

### Software Engineer

#### **Health Converge Pvt Ltd**

Health Converge team is building Web + Mobile applications to support hospitals and doctors

- Frontend Developer (Docezzy Enterprise http://www.docezzy.com/)
  - Developed app with Ember.js of a Hospital Information System.
  - Developed OPD and Pharmacy module.
- Frontend Developer (Docezzy Cloud)
  - Developed HIS Cloud Application using Ruby on Rails and MySQL.
  - Implemented Task Management System for Operation Theatre (OT)
  - Developed Masters System of this Application.
- · Mobile Developer (Mobile Cloud Project)
  - Developed Mobile Application using IONIC 2.
  - Used Angular 2 for UI development of the Application.
  - Developed Notification System using Google Firebase.
- · Mobile Developer (Feedback application)
  - Feedback System for Enterprise Application.
  - Developed Runtime Server Connectivity System for Inter Server link-

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# Creating Note taking app using LiveView and GenServer

#### abulasar.com

AbulAsar

Date period

- And the state of t ng-liveview-and-genserver-part-1
- Blog explains insights of GenServer by using it as a state management tool.
- Blog got published in Elixir Weekly newsletter along with Jose Valim's blog
- Surpassed 1000 views within 2 weeks.

### API Authentication in Elixir Phoenix

#### abulasar.com

∆hııl∆sar

Date period

Anttps://abulasar.com/api-authentication-in-elixir-p hoenix-part-1

**Publication Description** 

### **Building Realtime LiveView** App using Phoenix PubSub

#### abulasar.com

AbulAsar

Date period

https://abulasar.com/building-realtime-liveview-ap p-using-phoenix-pubsub

**Publication Description** 

# **EDUCATION**

# B.E (Computer Engineering)

Theem College of Engg (Mumbai **University**)

· Graduated with Distinction in Final year of B.E (Computer Engineering), 2015